Kevin Chien

(510) 999-2661 Github: <u>kev-chien</u> LinkedIn: <u>kevinchien17</u>

UC Berkeley EECS sophomore with 1+ years of React front-end software development and 2 years of web development. Developed projects in Java, Python, and JavaScript. Currently managing 3 websites.

Education

University of California, Berkeley

B.S. in Electrical Engineering and Computer Science (GPA: 3.78)

Aug 2016 - May 2020
Coursework: Algorithms and Intractable Problems*, Artificial Intelligence*, Data Structures and Algorithms,
Discrete Math & Probability, Computer Architecture, Foundations in Data Science

* in progress

Experience

Pioneers in Engineering Website - Project Manager (1 year), Developer (2 years)

Aug 2016 - Present

- Oversaw team and developed content and styles for http://pioneers.berkeley.edu to convey content for potential sponsors, 300+ students, and 24 high schools per season.
- ▶ Trained and managed team of 7 to redesign and implement 10+ pages of content using HTML, SCSS, Jekyll, JQuery, and Github to provide responsive content, reviewing pull requests.
- Built web app using Angular JS to query and display live competition scores from Google Sheets.

Pioneers in Engineering React UI Software Developer (1 year)

Aug 2016 - May 2017

- ▶ Developed cross-platform desktop app using React, ES6, Redux, and Electron for 300+ high school students to use to program robots.
- ▶ Designed, built and shipped UI features, including code editor preferences, cached settings, robot status indicators, animated tutorial, file I/O operations and Mocha unit tests.
- Worked as part of a team using Github and Travis CI, participating in code reviews

Additional Projects

Database | Data Structures Project

March 2017

- ▶ Designed and built SQL clone with Java OOP, with table read, select, conditionals, and join.
- Wrote comprehensive JUnit tests and worked using Git in a team of 2.

BearMaps | Data Structures Project

April 2017

- ▶ Built the Java back-end REST API of a web app to deliver scaled images for a map upon zoom-in/out.
- ▶ Implemented A* search to find the shortest path from any start to any destination on the map.

PacMan | Artificial Intelligence Project

March 2018

▶ Implemented AI algorithms in Python to play PacMan, through using Mini/Expecti-Max and A*.

Personal Website Jan 2017

▶ Built kevinchien.me for portfolio hosting using HTML, CSS, JS & Jekyll.

Other Work / Volunteer Experience

UC Berkeley EECS Department / DSEP

EECS Tutor/ ASE (Paid): Taught circuit analysis, linear algebra, and iPython in labs and OH
EECS Academic Intern: Taught in offices hours and labs for Data Structures.

DSEP Associate: Developed auto-graded iPython notebooks and taught data science.

Fall '17
Spring '18
Spring '18

Skills

Programming Languages: Python, Java, JavaScript, C, SQL, Lua, Bash, LaTeX, RISC-V

Front-End: React.js, JQuery, Jekyll, SCSS, Angular

Data Science: NumPy, matplotlib, Apache Spark, Data Inference, Data Visualization

Software: Git, Node, IntelliJ, Redux, ES6, Electron, JUnit, Travis CI, OpenMP, SIMD, Mac OSX, Linux,

Windows, Amazon EC2

Other: Memory management, Parallelism, Async, REST